pasadena.edu 2017-08-10

# Privacy - Pasadena City College - Pasadena City College

## Internet Privacy Policy

At Pasadena City College (PCC), we are committed to protecting your privacy and making it more efficient to interact with our Web site. We recognize your right to know what information is being collected about you and how that information will be used, as well as our legal obligations to limit collection and protect what we do collect. You do not have to give us personal information to visit our site. Sometimes we do need information to provide services that you request, and this commitment of privacy explains our online information practices. 

This policy is consistent with the provisions of the Internet Security and Privacy Act, the Freedom of Information Law, and the Personal Privacy Protection Law. Pasadena City College further complies with the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA) as it pertains to student records updated online. 

This Statement of Internet Privacy applies to the pasadena.edu Web site and governs data collection and usage. By using the pasadena.edu website, you consent to the data practices described in this statement. 

PCC does not collect any personal information about you unless you provide that information voluntarily by sending e-mail, completing an online request, registration or an application form. 

### Information Collected

The pasadena.edu Web site collects personal information (first and last name, home or other physical address, email address, telephone number, or other identifiers that permit the physical or online contacting of an individual) only if specifically and knowingly provided by you. For purposes of this policy, "personal information" means any information concerning a natural person which, because of name, number, symbol, mark, or other identifier, can be used to identify that natural person. 

The pasadena.edu Web site also collects anonymous demographic information for statistical purposes and the analyses of user behavior in order to measure interest in the various areas of our site. We will disclose this information to third parties only in aggregate form. 

### Information Collected Automatically When You Visit pasadena.edu

When visiting pasadena.edu, PCC automatically collects and stores the following information about your visit: 

  * The Internet domain (for example, "xcompany.com" if you use a private Internet access account) and IP address (an IP address is a number that is automatically assigned to your computer on the Internet. 
  * The type of browser used, its version and the operating system on which that browser is running 
  * The Web page from which you hyperlinked to the current Web page
  * The date and time of the visit
  * The pages that were visited and the amount of time spent at each page
  * None of the automatically collected information constitutes personal information by the Internet Privacy and Security Act. This automatically collected information is is collected for statistical analysis and is used to learn how users are interacting with our Web site and to maintain or improve the quality of the Web site. 

The automatically collected information is not collected for commercial marketing purposes and PCC is not authorized to sell or otherwise disclose the information collected from pasadena.edu for commercial marketing purposes. 

### Information You Send Via Email

During your visit to pasadena.edu you may send an email to PCC. Your e-mail address and the contents of your message will be collected. The information collected is not limited to text characters and may include audio, video, and graphic information formats included in the message. Your email address and the information included in your message will be used to respond to you, to address issues you identify, to improve this Web site, or to forward your message to another PCC department for appropriate action. Your e-mail address is not collected for commercial purposes and PCC is not authorized to sell or otherwise disclose your e-mail address for commercial purposes. Except for authorized law enforcement investigations or, as required by law, we do not share our email with any other organizations. 

Remember that e-mail is not necessarily secure against interception. If your communication is very sensitive, or includes information such as your bank account, charge card, or social security number, you should send it by mail. 

### Information You Submit to Us Via an Online Request, Application or Registration Form

During your visit to pasadena.edu you may complete a transaction such as an online application or an online information request form. The information collected by PCC, including personal information volunteered by you in completing the form, application or transaction, is used by PCC only for the purposes for which it was provided and will not be shared with another entity except as prescribed by law. Pasadena City College may provide or distribute certain lists and statistical reports of regulatory information as provided by law, but no personal information is sold or distributed for commercial purposes. 

PCC does not knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of 13 or create profiles of children under the age of 13. Users are cautioned, however, that the collection of personal information submitted in an email will be treated as though it was submitted by an adult, and may, unless exempted from access by federal or state law, be subject to public access. 

### Electronic Commerce Precautions

Some of our Web pages allow you to make donations, register and pay for classes, etc. In those instances, we will collect the information needed to fulfill your registration or acknowledge your contribution, just as though it had been made on paper. That information will be maintained and protected in accordance with the Privacy Act, 5 U.S.C. 552a, which means that it will be secured in transit to us and once received. Your contributions are processed through secure PayPal ecommerce solution. 

### Disclosure of Information Collected Through This Web site

The collection of information through pasadena.edu and the disclosure of that information are subject to the provisions of the Internet Security and Privacy Act. PCC will only collect personal information through pasadena.edu or disclose personal information collected through pasadena.edu if the user has consented to the collection or disclosure of such personal information. The voluntary disclosure of personal information to PCC by the user, constitutes consent to the collection and disclosure of the information by PCC for the purposes for which the user disclosed the information to PCC. 

However, PCC may collect or disclose personal information without consent if the collection or disclosure is: 

  1. necessary to perform the statutory duties of PCC, or necessary for PCC to operate a program authorized by law, or authorized by state or federal statute or regulation 
  2. made pursuant to a court order or by law
  3. for the purpose of validating the identity of the user
  4. of information to be used solely for statistical purposes that is in a form that cannot be used to identify any particular person. 

Further, the disclosure of information, including personal information, collected through pasadena.edu is subject to the provisions of the Freedom of Information Law, the Personal Privacy Protection Law and Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA). 

PCC may disclose personal information to federal or state law enforcement authorities to enforce its rights against unauthorized access or attempted unauthorized access to PCC's information technology assets. 

### Use of Your Personal Information

Pasadena City College may use your personally identifiable information to inform you of services provided and processes requiring your attention. PCC may also contact you via surveys to conduct research about your opinion of current services or of potential new services. 

### **Access to and Correction of Personal Information Collected through pasadena.edu**

Users have online access to some of their Internet collected personal information and are provided Internet access to update and correct information. Additionally any user may submit a request to PCC's Web Administrator to determine whether personal information pertaining to that user has been collected through pasadena.edu. Any such request shall be made in writing and must be accompanied by reasonable proof of identity of the user. Reasonable proof of identity may include verification of a signature, inclusion of an identifier generally known only to the user, or similar appropriate identification. 

The address of the Web Administrator is:

Pasadena City College  
Attn: Web Administrator, Building C, Room 145  
1570 E. Colorado Blvd.  
Pasadena, CA 91106 

The Web Administrator shall, within five (5) business days of the receipt of a proper request, provide access to the personal information; deny access in writing, explaining the reasons therefore; or acknowledge the receipt of the request in writing, stating the approximate date when the request will be granted or denied, which date shall not be more than thirty (30) days from the date of the acknowledgment. 

In the event that PCC has collected personal information pertaining to a user through pasadena.edu and that information is to be provided to the user pursuant to the userâ€™s request, the Web Administrator shall inform the user of his or her right to request that the personal information be amended or corrected under the procedures set forth in section 95 of the Public Officers Law. 

Additional information regarding the college's policies relating the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA) can be found here: /admissions/records/ferpa.cfm 

### Confidentiality and Integrity of Personal Information Collected Through pasadena.edu

PCC is strongly committed to protecting personal information collected through pasadena.edu against unauthorized access, use or disclosure. PCC has implemented procedures to safeguard the integrity of its information technology assets, including, but not limited to, authentication, authorization, monitoring, auditing, and encryption. These security procedures have been integrated into the design, implementation, and day-to-day operations of pasadena.edu, as well as limited employee access to personal information collected through pasadena.edu as part of our continuing commitment to the security of electronic content as well as the electronic transmission of information. 

PCC secures your personal information from unauthorized access, use or disclosure. PCC secures the personally identifiable information you provide on computer servers in a controlled, secure environment, protected from unauthorized access, use or disclosure. When personal information (such as a credit card number) is transmitted to other Web sites, it is protected through the use of encryption, such as the Secure Socket Layer (SSL) protocol. 

For Web site security purposes and to maintain the availability of pasadena.edu for all users, PCC employs software to monitor traffic to identify unauthorized attempts to upload or change information or otherwise damage pasadena.edu. 

Please keep in mind that if you directly disclose personally identifiable information or personally sensitive data through one of PCC's social network sites, such as Facebook®, Twitter®, YouTube® or WordPress® blog, this information may be collected and used by others. 

### **Other Web Sites Linked from Pasadena.edu**

PCC encourages you to review the privacy statements of Web sites you choose to visit from links on pasadena.edu. PCC is not responsible for the privacy statements or other content on Web sites outside of the Pasadena City College's family of Web sites. 

### **Cookies**

Cookies are small pieces of information that are stored by the user's browser on the hard drive of your computer. Pasadena.edu utilizes temporary and long lasting session cookies in certain portions of itâ€™s website to manage your interaction activities, such as Online Orientation completion and to provide convenience or personalized features to save you time, such as personalized Quick Links. You have the ability to accept or decline cookies via your browser preferences and may decline if you prefer. If you choose to decline cookies, you may not be able to fully experience the interactive features of this site. 

### Disclaimer

The information provided in this privacy policy should not be construed as giving business, legal, or other advice, or warranting as fail proof, the security of information provided through pasadena.edu. 

### **Limitation of Liability**

PCC attempts to maintain the highest accuracy of content on its web site. Any errors or omissions should be reported for investigation. 

PCC makes no claims, promises, or guarantees about the absolute accuracy, completeness, or adequacy of the contents of this web site and expressly disclaims liability for errors and omissions in the contents of this web site. No warranty of any kind, implied, expressed, or statutory, including but not limited to the warranties of non-infringement of third party rights, title, merchantability, fitness for a particular purpose, and freedom from computer virus, is given with respect to the contents of this web site or its hyperlinks to other Internet resources. References or links in this web site to any specific commercial products, processes, or services, or the use of any trade, firm, or corporation name are for the information and convenience of the public, and do not constitute endorsement, recommendation, or favoring by the State of California, or its employees or agents. 

### **Contact Information**

For questions regarding this Internet privacy policy, please contact the Web Administrator via e-mail at wecoord@pasadena.edu or by regular mail at: 

Pasadena City College  
Attn: Web Administrator, Building C, Room 145  
1570 E. Colorado Blvd.  
Pasadena, CA 91106 

If you believe that Pasadena City College has not adhered to this Internet Privacy Statement, please contact the above. We will use commercially reasonable efforts to promptly determine and remedy the problem. 

### **Changes to this Statement**

This Statement of Internet Privacy Policy is subject to change without notice.

PCC will occasionally update this Statement of Internet Privacy Policy as the conditions and website change. PCC encourages you to periodically review this Policy to be informed of how PCC is protecting your information.
